

Orange County, CA

jayesswang.comin @jayesswang

1 +1 626.278.0505

SUMMARY

Visual storyteller, strategic creative, and empathetic advocate of engaging user-centered experiences that align with business goals.

Perceptive and adaptable ENTP-A (Myers-Briggs) leveraging almost 20-yrs of work history in multiple industries and roles in the USA and Asia. Analytical problem-solver with a global perspective.

DESIGN PROCESS

Interviews
Surveys
Competitive analysis
User research
Field study
Personas
Info architecture
Flow diagrams
Sketches
Wireframing
Rapid prototyping
Usability testing
Heuristic evaluation

TOOLS

Figma
Sketch
Invision
Adobe CC
Axure
UsabilityHub
UserTesting
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
Github
G-Suite

LANGUAGE

Mandarin Chinese

RECENT PROJECTS

WHAT DO YOU MEME?TM MOBILE GAME | view case study

Convert a popular tabletop game for adults into a mobile game. Techniques used: online surveys, field study (observe real-time game play), contextual inquiry, card sorting, storyboarding, A/B testing, moderated usability testing. Tools used: G-Suite (Forms, Sheet), Figma, UsabilityHub, Loom, YouTube.

BOXLY | view case study

Design an SaaS that allows users to collect, store, and share info all from one place. Techniques used: online surveys, user stories, user flows, A/B testing, unmoderated usability testing (wireframes & mockups). Tools used: G-Suite (Forms, Sheet), Draw.io, Balsamiq, Sketch, InVision, UserTesting.

JW PORTFOLIO | view case study

Hand code a responsive portfolio website (drawing inspiration from Lynn Fisher, Jen Simmons, and CSS Zen Garden) and host it on GitHub Pages. Tools include Figma, UsabilityHub, Dreamweaver, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Github.

EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGN APPRENTICE | BLOC.IO | Remote

2018

Complete an **8-mth apprenticeship** under an experienced UX professional. Participate in synchronous **daily design critiques** and **weekly group sessions**; collaborate w/ my cohort via Slack; and complete 3 projects.

PHOTOGRAPHER | JW PHOTOGRAPHY | Los Angeles

2008 - 2018

Notable clients include: Bebe, HauteLook (Nordstrom), Halston, Ozsale.

IN-HOUSE PHOTOGRAPHER | FOREVER 21

2013 - 2017

Second-in-command to photography supervisor; **train** new photographers; shoot appealing images that **drive sales**; some duties exceed original job title and description. Demonstrate **corporate diplomacy and collaborate** across departments.

WEB PRODUCER | KAC MEDIA | Los Angeles

2010 - 2011

Produce content, **research** the story, **write** scripts, conduct **interviews**, create video rough drafts. **Start-up work culture** with small, nimble, and fluid teams. **Wear multiple hats**, assisting as needed in all tasks from pre- to post-production. **Resourceful** within a limited budget.

SENIOR EDITOR | ENVISION MBA | Taipei, Taiwan

2006 - 2010

Asia's #1 education consultancy tailoring **branding & strategy** for prospective applicants to **top 50 MBA programs** worldwide. Hundreds of **successful student placements at**: INSEAD, HEC Paris, London Business School, Wharton, Sloan, Columbia, Oxford, Haas, and many others.

EDUCATION

BLOC.IO | UX DESIGN APPRENTICESHIP

2018

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA (USC)

2006

B.A. in English & Creative Writing / Minor in Music Business